Ignacio González

London, United Kingdom <u>www.nachogl1.dev</u> i.gonzalezl@hotmail.com +44 7395454415

Profile

I'm Ignacio, I have been a Software Engineer for 4 years. I have been mainly working with Java but was also part of projects involving Typescript/Javascript in the healthcare industry and the consultancy space with clients in the retail and hospitality industry.

I am a motivated developer who takes ownership and knows how to be a team player. I care about what I do and my passion for it is visible as well as my drive to provide value to the team. I enjoy creating content in my free time and work on my own pet projects. You can find more information about me at www.nachogl1.dev

Skills

Backend: Java, Hibernate, Spring Boot, Thymeleaf, Typescript, awareness of bash

Frontend: Worked with React, Angular and Ionic.

DevOps & CI/CD: Git, BitBucket and worked with TeamCity, Trello, Confluence, Jira

Testing: TDD, Mocks, BDD, JUnit, Jest

Cloud: AWS

Observability: Grafana and AWS CloudWatch

Code Quality: Refactoring, Clean Code, DDD, Hexagonal Architecture, SOLID, Object Oriented Design, Code Reviews, Sonar, Patterns and Algorithms

Team Practices: Scrum, Kanban, Pair Programming

Relevant Experience

Software Craftsman - Codurance (April 2022 - Jul 2024)

Working in a technology agnostic software consultancy whose central core is composed of best practices, basics like SOLID principles, Agile and using practices like pair programming. Codurance's core values are Pragmatism, Excellence, Professionalism, Efficiency and Respect

Codurance - VeryChic: Search Engine

- Tech Stack: TS backend, Cucumber, AWS OpenSearch, Lambdas, EventBridge and CloudWatch, Git.
- Developing a new search engine to improve catalogue update time
- Working on the ETL layer that receives about bookings/accommodations
- Monitoring issues with CloudWatch logs
- Creation of a cron to trigger updates via Lambdas through AWS EventBridge
- Improve the way and performance that information gets updated in the search engine
- Focus on testability and maintainability of the backend
- Create/Improve rules that will instruct how to feed the information to the client in AWS OpenSearch
- Searches and geographical suggestions
- I was part of a few interviews for new developers for Codurance in the meantime

Codurance - Retail Company: Internal Platform

- Tech Stack: Java, Spring Boot, React, Typescript, Cypress, Karate, Sonar, Git Backend for Frontends and Microservices
- Big retail company who wanted to redesign an internal tool to connect all the business channels: Since the inception of the idea of a garment to the acquisition of supplier/materias to its creation
- Used Java for the BFF layer that will be the nexus between client and bounded contexts
- Focus on maintainability and testability of both back and frontend
- Used JIRA for backlog management and planning
- Facilitate group knowledge sharing with the team to avoid silos
- Participate in the development of activities for LSCC, led some internal groups involved in software content and content creation for Codurance like blog posts and katas

Java Developer – Ziath (August 2019 - Jan 2022)

The company focused on manufacturing equipment for laboratories from the inception of the idea to the end of the product: Scanners, readers and robotics.

Main Desktop Application

- Tech Stack: Java and Angular 8, Spring Boot, Maven, Git, electron, jenkins and teamCity
- Improve the desktop application that will be the nexus between the scanner and the user
- Focused on user experience for the angular application
- Helped develop solutions to improve the performance of the barcode reading process in the server
- Help develop the frontend since its inception as the legacy tool used JavaFx and Swing.
- Attend client meetings and showcasing the software in different conferences, solving real time problems with clients

- Provide user support
- Provided new ideas for the team to improve workflows like kanban style and use of productivity tools like trello

Mobile Application

- Tech Stack: Angular 8, npm, Git, ionic
- Improve the mobile application that will be the nexus between the scanner and the user
- Help increasing maintainability for the code that was used for desktop and mobile

Internal tool - DocGen2

- Tech Stack: Java, Spring Boot, Hibernate, maven, Git, thymeleaf
- In charge of the development of the application that will product all the necessary documentation to be added for each shipment depending on the geographical area of the client
- Develop the model and the MVCS design of the whole project
- Used hibernate for the persistence of the project
- Develop the views using Thymeleaf and CSS for styling the produced documents
- Keep a constant feedback loop with the domain expert (Operations Department and Sales)
- User support
- Manual deployment only accessible for internal office network

Independent Internal Control for Scanner based on Raspberry Pi

- Tech Stack: Linux debian, Bash
- Start the development of a new scanner attachment that will help the user interact with the scanner via touchscreen rather than the desktop/mobile application. The raspberry will run the main desktop application in kiosk mode.
- Prepare the touchscreen in a kiosk mode, limiting the user interactions
- Develop the keyboard feature for the user to interact with forms
- Learn networking concepts during the development

Legacy Main Desktop application

- Tech Stack: Java, Javafx and swing
- Occasionally help maintain the codebase and fixing errors

Intern, Calidad Pascual, Madrid, Spain (Mar-Jun 2018)

Fab-Lab, University San Pablo CEU, Madrid, Spain (Mar-Jul 2018)

Student Researcher, CNIC, Madrid, Spain (Sep 2016-May 2017)

Education

Stock Market and Financial Derivatives Certificate, UNED (Dec 2020-Oct 2021) - Just for fun

1:1 MSc Computer Science, University of Greenwich, London (Sep 2018-Sep 2019)

BSc Bilingual Biomedical Engineering, University of San Pablo CEU, Madrid, Spain (Sep 2013-Jul 2018)

Additional Experience

Bar Staff, Lower Deck, University of Greenwich, London (Sep 2018-June 2019)

The main purpose of this activity was improving my English level and gaining confidence in a new environment at the same time I was monetizing my time.

Additional skills

Spanish: NativeEnglish: AdvancedDriving licence

References available on request